Half of the human workforce is expected to be replaced
未来二十年内，一半的人类劳动力
by software and robots in the next 20 years.
将会被软件和机器人取代。
And many corporate leaders welcome that as a chance to increase profits.
一些企业家把它视为增加利润的好机会，
Machines are more efficient;
因为机器更高效，
humans are complicated and difficult to manage.
而人类更复杂且难于管理。
Well, I want our organizations to remain human.
而我希望我们的组织保留人类，
In fact, I want them to become beautiful.
事实上，我希望它们变得更美。
Because as machines take our jobs and do them more efficiently,
由于机器可以取代我们，并且更高效地工作，
soon the only work left for us humans will be the kind of work
很快，留给人类解决的就会只剩那些
that must be done beautifully rather than efficiently.
需要美感而非效率的工作。
To maintain our humanity in the this second Machine Age,
要在第二次机器时代维持人的作用，
we may have no other choice than to create beauty.
我们别无选择，只能创造美。
Beauty is an elusive concept.
美是一个难以捉摸的概念。
For the writer Stendhal it was the promise of happiness.
作家司汤达说美是一种幸福的承诺。
For me it's a goal by Lionel Messi.
而对我来说，美是梅西的一记进球。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
So bear with me as I am proposing four admittedly very subjective principles
所以，请容许我提出四个相当主观的原则，
that you can use to build a beautiful organization.
它们可以被用来建立美的机构。
First: do the unnecessary.
第一，做不必要的事。
[Do the Unnecessary]
[做不必要的事]
A few months ago, Hamdi Ulukaya,
几个月前，哈姆迪·乌鲁卡亚，
the CEO and founder of the yogurt company Chobani,
Chobani 酸奶工厂的创始人和 CEO，
made headlines when he decided to grant stock to all of his 2,000 employees.
为他2000名全体员工授予了股份，并因此上了头条。
Some called it a PR stunt,
有人说这是公关噱头，
others -- a genuine act of giving back.
有人认为这是一种慷慨的回馈。
But there is something else that was remarkable about it.
但还有些更不寻常的值得注意之处。
It came completely out of the blue.
这个消息突如其来，
There had been no market or stakeholder pressure,
没有市场或股东的压力，
and employees were so surprised
员工们也非常意外，
that they burst into tears when they heard the news.
以至于他们听到消息时喜极而泣。
Actions like Ulukaya's are beautiful because they catch us off guard.
像乌鲁卡亚这样的行为就是美的，它瞬间击中人心。
They create something out of nothing
他们凭空创造了一些东西，
because they're completely unnecessary.
而这些东西看起来完全没有必要。
I once worked at a company
我曾在一家
that was the result of a merger
由一家大型IT外包公司
of a large IT outsourcing firm and a small design firm.
和一家小设计公司合并而成的公司工作过。
We were merging 9,000 software engineers with 1,000 creative types.
我们要把9000名软件工程师和1000名创意工作者整合在一起工作。
And to unify these immensely different cultures,
为了融合这两种截然不同的文化，
we were going to launch a third, new brand.
我们要建立一个全新的品牌。
And the new brand color was going to be orange.
新的品牌商标是橙色的，
And as we were going through the budget for the rollouts,
我们在讨论品牌推广预算时，
we decided last minute
在最后一分钟，
to cut the purchase of 10,000 orange balloons,
我们决定砍掉购买一万只橙色气球的计划，
which we had meant to distribute to all staff worldwide.
我们本想把这些气球发给全球员工。
They just seemed unnecessary and cute in the end.
这件事看起来没有必要，只是为了好玩。
I didn't know back then
当时我并不知道，
that our decision marked the beginning of the end --
我们的决定预示了结局——
that these two organizations would never become one.
两家公司不可能顺利合并。
And sure enough, the merger eventually failed.
果然，合并以失败告终。
Now, was it because there weren't any orange balloons?
就因为当时没买气球吗？
No, of course not.
不，当然不是。
But the kill-the-orange-balloons mentality permeated everything else.
但是这种砍掉气球的心态弥漫到了其他所有事情上。
You might not always realize it, but when you cut the unnecessary,
你可能不会意识到，但在你砍掉“不必要”的时候，
you cut everything.
你其实砍掉了所有。
Leading with beauty means rising above what is merely necessary.
追求美，意味着超越单纯的必需。
So do not kill your orange balloons.
所以，不要砍掉你的橙色气球。
The second principle:
第二个原则：
create intimacy.
创造亲密感。
[Create Intimacy]
[创造亲密感]
Studies show that how we feel about our workplace
研究表明，我们对工作的感受，
very much depends on the relationships with our coworkers.
很大程度上取决于我们和同事的人际关系。
And what are relationships other than a string of microinteractions?
除了每天简单的交流，人际关系还包括什么呢？
There are hundreds of these every day in our organizations
我们每天在公司有几百次这样的机会，
that have the potential to distinguish a good life from a beautiful one.
可以让普通的一天变成美丽的一天。
The marriage researcher John Gottman says
婚姻研究者约翰·戈特曼说，
that the secret of a healthy relationship
健康关系的秘密，
is not the great gesture or the lofty promise,
不在于伟大的姿态或崇高的承诺，
it's small moments of attachment.
而在于细小的展现人与人关系的瞬间。
In other words, intimacy.
换句话说，就是亲密感。
In our networked organizations,
在我们网络化的组织中，
we tout the strength of weak ties
我们更加青睐弱连接的关系，
but we underestimate the strength of strong ones.
但我们同时低估了强连接的力量。
We forget the words of the writer Richard Bach who once said,
我们忘记了作家Richard Bach说过的话：
"Intimacy --
“亲密感——
not connectedness --
不是连通——
intimacy is the opposite of loneliness."
亲密感，是孤独的反义词。”
So how do we design for organizational intimacy?
所以我们该如何设计才能增进组织的亲密性？
The humanitarian organization CARE
一个叫 CARE 的人道组织
wanted to launch a campaign on gender equality in villages in northern India.
想要在印度北部的村庄发起性别平等运动。
But it realized quickly
但他们很快意识到，
that it had to have this conversation first with its own staff.
他们首先需要同内部成员展开交流。
So it invited all 36 team members and their partners
所以他们邀请了36位团队成员和他们的搭档，
to one of the Khajuraho Temples,
去了克久拉霍的一个庙宇，
known for their famous erotic sculptures.
这个庙宇因色情佛像而闻名。
And there they openly discussed their personal relationships --
在那里，他们与同事和搭档一起，
their own experiences of gender equality
坦诚地讨论他们的私人关系——
with the coworkers and the partners.
他们自己对性别平等的体会。
It was eye-opening for the participants.
这令参与者们深受启发，
Not only did it allow them to relate to the communities they serve,
这不仅帮他们在自己与服务的社区之间建立了连结，
it also broke down invisible barriers
更打破了无形的障碍，
and created a lasting bond amongst themselves.
在他们之间建立了持久的团结。
Not a single team member quit in the next four years.
结果，在接下来的四年中，没有一个成员退出。
So this is how you create intimacy.
所以，这就是建立亲密感的方法，
No masks ...
没有面具，
or lots of masks.
或者，有很多面具——
(Laughter)
（笑声）
When Danone, the food company,
在达能食品公司想要
wanted to translate its new company manifesto into product initiatives,
把新的公司宣言落实为产品计划时，
it gathered the management team
他们召集了管理团队
and 100 employees from across different departments, seniority levels and regions
和来自不同部门、不同层级和地区的 100名员工，
for a three-day strategy retreat.
举办了为期三天的战略会议。
And it asked everybody to wear costumes for the entire meeting:
他们要求每个人都这么打扮：
wigs, crazy hats, feather boas,
假发、夸张的帽子、羽毛围巾、
huge glasses and so on.
大眼镜，等等。
And they left with concrete outcomes
他们都热情高涨，
and full of enthusiasm.
并且实现了了很实质性的成果。
And when I asked the woman who had designed this experience
我问一位女士，谁设计了这个方式，
why it worked,
为什么这么有效，
she simply said, "Never underestimate the power of a ridiculous wig."
她随口说道：“永远不要低估搞笑假发的力量。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
(Applause)
（掌声）
Because wigs erase hierarchy,
因为假发消除了层级，
and hierarchy kills intimacy --
而层级会扼杀亲密感——
both ways,
不管对CEO还是实习生
for the CEO and the intern.
都是如此。
Wigs allow us to use the disguise of the false
假发让我们能依托一种伪装，
to show something true about ourselves.
来展示真实的自己。
And that's not easy in our everyday work lives,
在我们日常的工作中是不容易做到的，
because the relationship with our organizations
因为我们的组织中的人际关系，
is often like that of a married couple that has grown apart,
经常像日渐疏远的夫妻一样，
suffered betrayals and disappointments,
充满背叛和失望，
and is now desperate to be beautiful for one another once again.
现在不顾一切地想要重修旧好。
And for either of us the first step towards beauty involves a huge risk.
对我们每个人来说，通向美的第一步都隐含巨大的风险。
The risk to be ugly.
变丑的风险。
[Be Ugly]
[变丑]
So many organizations these days are keen on designing beautiful workplaces
现在很多组织想要设计美丽的办公区，
that look like anything but work:
让它们看起来像度假区、咖啡店、游乐场、大学校园，
vacation resorts, coffee shops, playgrounds or college campuses --
而偏偏不像是用来工作的。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Based on the promises of positive psychology,
基于积极心理学的考虑，
we speak of play and gamification,
我们把工作变成玩耍、游戏，
and one start-up even says that when someone gets fired,
甚至有创业公司在解雇员工的时候，
they have graduated.
说他们是“毕业”了。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
That kind of beautiful language only goes "skin deep,
这些美丽的语言是“肤浅的，
but ugly cuts clean to the bone,"
但丑陋却可以深入骨髓，”
as the writer Dorothy Parker once put it.
这是作家多萝西·帕克的原话。
To be authentic is to be ugly.
坦白事实，就意味着丑陋。
It doesn't mean that you can't have fun or must give in to the vulgar or cynical,
这不是说你不能开心，或者必须向庸俗和自私妥协，
but it does mean that you speak the actual ugly truth.
而是你应该说出丑陋的事实。
Like this manufacturer
就像这位想要改善
that wanted to transform one of its struggling business units.
他经营不佳的业务的企业家。
It identified, named and pinned on large boards all the issues --
他们把所有的阻碍业绩的问题归类、命名，
and there were hundreds of them --
并钉在大白板上，
that had become obstacles to better performance.
有几百项之多。
They put them on boards, moved them all into one room,
他们把这些白板搬到一个房间，
which they called "the ugly room."
被他们称为“丑陋之屋”。
The ugly became visible for everyone to see --
这些丑陋被暴露在灯光下——
it was celebrated.
每个人都可以看到。
And the ugly room served as a mix of mirror exhibition and operating room --
这个房间变成了镜子展厅和手术室的结合——
a biopsy on the living flesh to cut out all the bureaucracy.
用来切除官僚主义的手术室。
The ugliest part of our body is our brain.
我们身体中最丑陋的部分是大脑。
Literally and neurologically.
不仅看上去很丑陋，
Our brain renders ugly what is unfamiliar ...
还会创造人们不熟悉的丑陋的东西，
modern art, atonal music,
现代艺术，无调音乐，
jazz, maybe --
爵士乐，也可能——
VR goggles for that matter --
还有VR眼镜——
strange objects, sounds and people.
奇怪的东西、声音和人。
But we've all been ugly once.
但我们每个人都曾丑陋过，
We were a weird-looking baby,
我们曾经是外表奇怪的婴儿，
a new kid on the block, a foreigner.
街区新来的小孩，或一个外来者。
And we will be ugly again when we don't belong.
我们离去时也会再次变得丑陋。
The Center for Political Beauty,
柏林一个叫“政治美好中心”的
an activist collective in Berlin,
社会活动团体，
recently staged an extreme artistic intervention.
近期上演了一个极端艺术事件。
With the permission of relatives,
经过家属同意，
it exhumed the corpses of refugees who had drowned at Europe's borders,
他们掘出在欧洲边境溺水身亡的难民遗体，
transported them all the way to Berlin,
运送到柏林，
and then reburied them at the heart of the German capital.
把他们葬在德国首都的中心。
The idea was to allow them to reach their desired destination,
这个计划想让他们抵达曾经渴望的目的地，
if only after their death.
即便是在他们死去之后。
Such acts of beautification may not be pretty,
这种美化行为可能不太优雅，
but they are much needed.
但它们很有必要。
Because things tend to get ugly when there's only one meaning, one truth,
因为如果只有一种意义，一个真相，只有答案，没有问题的话，
only answers and no questions.
事情就会变得丑陋。
Beautiful organizations keep asking questions.
美的组织会持续提出问题。
They remain incomplete,
它们保持不完整的状态，
which is the fourth and the last of the principles.
这是第四个，也是最后一个原则。
[Remain Incomplete]
[保持不完整]
Recently I was in Paris,
最近我去了趟巴黎，
and a friend of mine took me to Nuit Debout,
我的一个朋友带我去了Nuit Debout，
which stands for "up all night,"
意思是“不眠之夜”，
the self-organized protest movement
始于为反对法国劳动法提案而产生的
that had formed in response to the proposed labor laws in France.
一个自发抗议运动。
Every night, hundreds gathered at the Place de la République.
每天晚上，几百人聚集在共和国广场，
Every night they set up a small, temporary village
每天晚上，他们都会搭建起一个临时村庄，
to deliberate their own vision of the French Republic.
讨论他们自己理想中的法兰西共和国。
And at the core of this adhocracy
这个组织的核心是一个全体大会，
was a general assembly where anybody could speak
在会上，每个人都可以用
using a specially designed sign language.
一种特别设计的手语来交流。
Like Occupy Wall Street and other protest movements,
就像占领华尔街及其他抗议运动一样，
Nuit Debout was born in the face of crisis.
“不眠之夜”也是在面对危机时诞生。
It was messy --
它很混乱——
full of controversies and contradictions.
充满争论和矛盾。
But whether you agreed with the movement's goals or not,
不管你是否认同他们的抗议诉求，
every gathering was a beautiful lesson in raw humanity.
每次集会都是一次原旨人权的大课堂。
And how fitting that Paris --
巴黎——
the city of ideals, the city of beauty --
这个理想之城，美好之城——
was it's stage.
正是最合适他们的舞台。
It reminds us that like great cities,
它提醒我们，就像伟大的城市一样，
the most beautiful organizations are ideas worth fighting for --
最美好的组织，是值得为之奉献理想的——
even and especially when their outcome is uncertain.
即使，也恰是，当它们的结果不确定的时候。
They are movements;
它们是运动，
they are always imperfect, never fully organized,
它们永远不完美，永远不会组织完整，
so they avoid ever becoming banal.
所以它们可以避免变得平庸。
They have something but we don't know what it is.
它们有一些无以言状的东西。
They remain mysterious; we can't take our eyes off them.
它们保持神秘，让我们无法忽视。
We find them beautiful.
我们发现它们很美。
So to do the unnecessary,
所以，做不必要的事，
to create intimacy,
创造亲密感，
to be ugly,
变丑，
to remain incomplete --
保持不完整——
these are not only the qualities of beautiful organizations,
它们不只是美的组织的特征，
these are inherently human characteristics.
它们也是人类固有的特征。
And these are also the qualities of what we call home.
更是我们称之为“家”的特征。
And as we disrupt, and are disrupted,
我们在干扰或被干扰时，
the least we can do is to ensure
我们至少可以确保
that we still feel at home in our organizations,
自己在组织中就像在家一样，
and that we use our organizations to create that feeling for others.
确保我们在组织中为他人营造同样的感受。
Beauty can save the world when we embrace these principles
当我们拥抱这些原则并为之努力，
and design for them.
美会拯救这个世界。
In the face of artificial intelligence and machine learning,
在人工智能和机器学习面前，
we need a new radical humanism.
我们需要一种全新的彻底的人文主义。
We must acquire and promote a new aesthetic and sentimental education.
我们必须学习并发展新的审美和感性教育。
Because if we don't,
因为如果我们不这么做，
we might end up feeling like aliens
最终我们可能在遍布智能机器的、
in organizations and societies that are full of smart machines
不懂得欣赏美的组织和社会中，
that have no appreciation whatsoever
像局外人一样疏离地活着——
for the unnecessary,
对不必要的事、
the intimate,
对亲密感、
the incomplete
对不完整、
and definitely not for the ugly.
当然也对丑陋，无动于衷。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）